KATIE JERGENS

407 State St., #3C, Brooklyn, NY 11217

469-305-2843

katie.jergens@gmail.com

SUMMARY

User experience design professional with expertise in conceptualizing, prototyping, and testing software applications. Adjust prototypes based on user study results so that the final designs are backed by strong evidence they will succeed in the marketplace. Industries include education-technology, insurance business operations, and online retail. Uniquely empowered with a formal computer science education which promotes clear and easy communication with developers as well as anticipation of technical limits and opportunities.

COMPETENCIES

- 3 1/2 years as user experience designer, 2 of those as a design lead
- 8 years as a quality assurance manager and automation engineer
- 5 years as software engineer
- Tools include in OmniGraffle, Adobe Fireworks, Sketch, Balsamiq, HTML/CSS/Javascript

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Amplify Education Inc., Brooklyn, NY

2011 - 2015

UX Designer / UX Lead

- Eased work of classroom teachers by designing online assessment, grading and reporting applications which pin-point student strengths and weaknesses and group students with similar educational needs.
- Improved analysis by school administrators by creating data visualizations that show strengths and weaknesses of classes, teachers, and schools, enabling administrators to fix problems and spread good practices.
- Exposed internal development and business teams to relevant customer data by compiling user research into searchable data bank.
- Created interactive prototypes in HTML/CSS/Javascript enabling development and business teams to see all phases of the application and allowing for accurate estimations and better communication with stakeholders.
- Authored Amplify's official design guidelines document, promoting consistent and high-quality designs throughout the company.

Wireless Generation, Inc., Brooklyn, NY

2004 - 2011

Quality Analyst Manager and Automation Engineer

- Modernized the team's skills by coaching QA analysts on latest testing and automation practices.
- Implemented an automated testing framework for an ETL schema, enabling fast and accurate testing of large data sets.
- Manually tested APIs, report queries, and front-end features, enabling the business to be confident that the software would be bug-free and pleasant to use in the hands of real users.

AMS Services, Inc., Bothell, WA

Software Developer IV

• Developed client-side software in C# and T-SL that enabled small-to-mid-sized insurance agencies to manage their business.

DailyShopper Networks, Seattle, WA

1999 - 2001

Software Developer II

- Developed online shopping website in ASP, XML, and T-SQL.
- Developed internal data entry tool in C++ which enabled easy and cheap entry of retail information.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Villanova University

VOLUNTEERING

The Dalton School 2015 – Present

- Teach high-school-level computer science.
- Develop curriculum for the computer science program.

CodeSpeak Labs 2015

• Mentor students age 5-12 on the fundamentals of computer science in a self-paced, individually-tailored environment.

Girls Who Code 2014 – 2015

- Taught high school girls the fundamentals of computer science in a project-based class.
- Mentored a Samsung Technovation High School Challenge team which designed and prototyped a mobile application to find employment for disenfranchised New Yorkers.

UNRELATED INTERESTS AND EXPERIENCES:

Marathon runner (2012), Oxford Literary Festival writing student (2012), Performer in Off-Broadway show (2007-2011), Stella Adler Studio of Acting student (2004-2006)

AWARDS, SCHOLARSHIPS & ASSOCIATIONS:

- Member AIGA-NY and Women Who Code-NYC (present)
- Cum Laude Villanova University
- President Villanova Chapter of ACM (Association for Computing Machinery)
- Member Upsilon Pi Epsilon (college computer science honors society)
- Winner NASA Launch Control Center Co-op position
- Winner Tandy Technology Scholarship
- Winner Society of Women Engineers Award
- Winner New Jersey Scholar-Athlete (high school)
- Winner Outstanding Volunteerism Scholarship Award (high school)

2001 - 2004